BECAUSE A CIVILIZED MAN CANNOT
PHYSICALLY FIGHT HIS PARTNER HIS
PRIMAL BRAIN IS LEFT WITH
ONLY ONE ESCAPE ROUTE HE
COMPLETELY SHUTS DOWN HE STOPS
MAKING EYE CONTACT HE GIVES
ONE-WORD ANSWERS HE CROSSES HIS
ARMS AND STARES INTO BLANK
SPACE THIS IS THE BEHAVIOR
PSYCHOLOGISTS CALL STONEWALLING LOOK AT
THE TRAGIC IRONY OF THIS
MOMENT TO HER HIS SILENCE
FEELS LIKE EMOTIONAL ABANDONMENT THE
ULTIMATE LACK OF LOVE TO
HIM HIS SILENCE IS AN
ACT OF EXTREME DISCIPLINE HE
IS BITING HIS TONGUE SO
HE DOESN'T INCINERATE THE RELATIONSHIP
IN A FIT OF RAGE
SHE SCREAMS LOUDER TO BREAK
THROUGH THE WALL HE BUILDS
THE WALL HIGHER TO SURVIVE
THE STORM